<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./FGDC_Plus.xsl"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>Caribbean Mangroves</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The mangrove map displays data from multiple sources, providing the most accurate and current information for this region to date. The first step towards this final product began with mapping regional data which covered as many countries in the CLME region as possible. This included information from 3 separate datasets: (1.) For the insular Caribbean, the best available information was compiled by Brigham Young University students through a TNC contract in 2011. This effort also began with a compilation of various datasets, supplemented with any original digitization efforts. This information was then checked against high resolution satellite imagery where available from Bing and Esri imagery basemaps. Errors and misrepresentations in the base information were modified through heads up digitization from the high resolution imagery. Omissions of coverage were corrected by creating new polygons to match visible coral structures. Outside of the insular Caribbean, (2.) the data from the Mesoamerican region was collected in 2007 as well as (3.) a "World Atlas of Mangroves" file collected from Mark Spalding in 2012. This dataset has been created as part of a collaboration between Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO), International Society for Mangrove Ecosystems (ISME), the International Tropical Timber Organization (ITTO), the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization Man and the Biosphere Programme (UNESCO-MAB), the United Nations Environment Programme – World Conservation Monitoring Centre (UNEP-WCMC) and the United Nations University Institute for Water, Environment and Health (UNU-INWEH) to revise the 1997 World Alas of Mangroves. The regional data was then replaced with sub-regional, national or site level information where this information was available (and wasn't already used in the starting regional file) to obtain a finer scale product. For mangroves, the following separate datasets were included: (1.) Grenada and St. Vincent and the Grenadines were replaced with data collected from the At the Water’s Edge Project led by the Nature Conservancy. The spatial information comes from four different datasets. a.) Contract work by Matthew Jones where he used existing data from Landsat and improved upon these shapes using Bing and ESRI imagery base maps in 2011. b.) The Ph.D. work of Kim Baldwin at the University of the West Indies Cave Hill and the generation of the Marine Space-use Information System (MarSIS) in 2009 resulted in a benthic habitat file which she created by heads up digitizing effort using IKONOS imagery. c.) Brigham Young University students, under contract by the Nature Conservancy, digitized polygons for the country of Grenada using WorldView2 2010 orthophotos. Mangroves for St. Vincent and the Grenadines were digitized from 2007 aerial photos. d.) field verification of mangrove patches by Gregg Moore of the University of New Hampshire in 2012 (2.) Some of the USVI and Puerto Rico polygons were replaced with and some were added from data collected from NOAA's benthic habitat mapping effort in 1999. Twenty-one distinct benthic habitat types within eight zones were mapped using visual interpretation of orthorectified aerial photographs. (3.) St. Lucia was replaced with data collected for the 2009 National Ecological GAP Assessment. Mangrove locations were collected from Mr. Allan Smith and manually digitized from 2004 aerial photography. (4.) Barbuda was missing from the regional data. Polygons were added using a national level landcover file created from 2004 imagery. (5.) Andros Island in the Bahamas was replaced with data collected from the Andros Island Conservation Assessment Project (CAP) in 2006 mapped by using a combination of local and scientific knowledge and land cover classes delineated from Landsat 7 imagery.</abstract>
      <purpose>5 files were created for the Caribbean Large Marine Ecosystem (CLME) Project: Protected Areas, Mangroves, Seagrasses, Beaches, and Coral Reefs. The purpose of the CLME Project was to improve the management of the shared living marine resources -most of which are considered to be fully or partially exploited- among participating countries in the Wider Caribbean Region through an Ecosystem-Based Management (EBM) approach.
</purpose>
    </descript>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-90.511332</westbc>
        <eastbc>-41.650873</eastbc>
        <northbc>27.260827</northbc>
        <southbc>-3.301516</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Mangroves</themekey>
        <themekey>Caribbean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/). By using this information, you agree to these terms.</useconst>
    <datacred>These files were created under a contract from UNESCO for the purposes of the CLME Project in 2013.</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.1.1.3143</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>45</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>WGS 1984 Web Mercator Auxiliary Sphere</mapprojn>
          <mapprojp>
            <otherprj>PROJCS["WGS_1984_Web_Mercator_Auxiliary_Sphere",GEOGCS["GCS_WGS_1984",DATUM["D_WGS_1984",SPHEROID["WGS_1984",6378137.0,298.257223563]],PRIMEM["Greenwich",0.0],UNIT["Degree",0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION["Mercator_Auxiliary_Sphere"],PARAMETER["False_Easting",0.0],PARAMETER["False_Northing",0.0],PARAMETER["Central_Meridian",0.0],PARAMETER["Standard_Parallel_1",0.0],PARAMETER["Auxiliary_Sphere_Type",0.0],UNIT["Meter",1.0],AUTHORITY["EPSG",3857]]-20037700-3024110010000-10000010000-100000100000.0010.0010.001true1021003857</otherprj>
          </mapprojp>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.0001</absres>
            <ordres>0.0001</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meter</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D WGS 1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS 1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257223563</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>MOW_Caribbean_Mangrove</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Hab_Desc</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Country</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Source</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Data_Year</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape_Area</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20150617</metd>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>