<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./FGDC_Plus.xsl"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>David Revell, Environmental Science Associates - Philip Williams and Associates, Coastal Geomorphologist</origin>
        <origin>Elena Vandebroek, Environmental Science Associates - Philip Williams and Associates, Hydrologist</origin>
        <title>Coastal Resilience Ventura: Coastal Hazards Mapping</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This polygon represents the potential extent of flooding caused by coastal processes during a large coastal storm wave event for low sea level rise (44 cm by 2100, relative to 2010) in 2030. The coastal storm flood hazard zones were developed using representative wave conditions based on observed historical events, with added sea level rise. Two components of coastal flooding are incorporated in this hazard area: flooding caused by storm waves rushing inland and flooding due to ocean storm characteristics such as storm surge (a rise in the ocean water level caused by waves and pressure changes during a storm). This hazard zone takes into account areas that are projected to erode in the future, sometimes leading to additional flooding through new hydraulic connections between the ocean and low-lying areas. This feature is one in a series of coastal flood and erosion hazard zones developed as part of the Coastal Resilience Ventura project. For detailed documentation about how these hazard zones were developed please see "Coastal Resilience Ventura: Technical Report for Coastal Hazards Mapping," a report prepared by ESA PWA for The Nature Conservancy.</abstract>
      <purpose>This polygon was created for estimating the impacts of future coastal flooding on the Ventura County coastline.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-119.485735</westbc>
        <eastbc>-118.940795</eastbc>
        <northbc>34.389378</northbc>
        <southbc>34.032905</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>climate change</themekey>
        <themekey>sea level rise</themekey>
        <themekey>coastal erosion</themekey>
        <themekey>flooding</themekey>
        <themekey>coastal hazards</themekey>
        <themekey>adaptation</themekey>
        <themekey>waves</themekey>
        <themekey>planning</themekey>
        <themekey>coastal management</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
        <themekey>oceans</themekey>
        <themekey>planningCadastre</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Funding Agencies
These data and report were prepared as the result of work funded by The Nature Conservancy, County of Ventura, and the California Coastal Conservancy (collectively "the funding agencies"). It does not necessarily represent the views of the funding agencies, their respective officers, agents and employees, subcontractors, or the State of California. The funding agencies, the State of California, and their respective officers, employees, agents, contractors, and subcontractors make no warrant, express or implied, and assume no responsibility or liability for the results of any actions taken or other information developed based on this report; nor does any party represent that the uses of this information will not infringe upon privately owned rights. These study results are being made available for informational purposes only and have not been approved or disapproved by the funding agencies, nor have the funding agencies passed upon the accuracy, currency, completeness, or adequacy of the information in this report. Users of this information agree by their use to hold blameless each of the funding agencies, study participants and authors for any liability associated with its use in any form. 

ESA PWA
This information is intended to be used for planning purposes only. Site-specific evaluations may be needed to confirm/verify information presented in this dataset. Inaccuracies may exist, and ESA PWA implies no warranties or guarantees regarding any aspect or use of this information. Further, any user of this data assumes all responsibility for the use thereof, and further agrees to hold ESA PWA harmless from and against any damage, loss, or liability arising from any use of this information. 
Commercial use of this information by anyone other than ESA PWA is prohibited. 
</accconst>
    <useconst>Funding Agencies:These data and report were prepared as the result of work funded by The Nature Conservancy, County of Ventura, and the California Coastal Conservancy (collectively "the funding agencies"). It does not necessarily represent the views of the funding agencies, their respective officers, agents and employees, subcontractors, or the State of California. The funding agencies, the State of California, and their respective officers, employees, agents, contractors, and subcontractors make no warrant, express or implied, and assume no responsibility or liability for the results of any actions taken or other information developed based on this report; nor does any party represent that the uses of this information will not infringe upon privately owned rights. These study results are being made available for informational purposes only and have not been approved or disapproved by the funding agencies, nor have the funding agencies passed upon the accuracy, currency, completeness, or adequacy of the information in this report. Users of this information agree by their use to hold blameless each of the funding agencies, study participants and authors for any liability associated with its use in any form. ESA PWA:This information is intended to be used for planning purposes only. Site-specific evaluations may be needed to confirm/verify information presented in this dataset. Inaccuracies may exist, and Environmental Science Associates (ESA) implies no warranties or guarantees regarding any aspect or use of this information. Further, any user of this data assumes all responsibility for the use thereof, and further agrees to hold ESA PWA harmless from and against any damage, loss, or liability arising from any use of this information. Commercial use of this information by anyone other than ESA is prohibited. Data Usage:These data are freely redistributable with proper metadata and source attribution. Please reference ESA PWA and The Nature Conservancy as the originator of the datasets in any future products or research derived from these data. The data are provided "as is" without any representations or warranties as to their accuracy, completeness, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. Data are based on model simulations, which are subject to revisions and updates and do not take into account many variables that could have substantial effects on erosion, flood extent and depth. Real world results will differ from results shown in the data. Site-specific evaluations may be needed to confirm/verify information presented in this dataset. This work shall not be used to assess actual coastal hazards, insurance requirements or property values, and specifically shall not be used in lieu of Flood insurance Studies and Flood Insurance Rate Maps issued by FEMA.</useconst>
    <datacred>Environmental Science Associates - Philip Williams and Associates (ESA PWA), San Francisco and The Nature Conservancy</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.1.1.3143</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>568</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>NAD 1983 UTM Zone 11N</mapprojn>
          <transmer>
            <sfctrmer>0.9996</sfctrmer>
            <longcm>-117.0</longcm>
            <latprjo>0.0</latprjo>
            <feast>500000.0</feast>
            <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
          </transmer>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000002220024164500956</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000002220024164500956</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meter</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D North American 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>coastal_storm_floodHZ_s12030</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape_Leng</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape_Area</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Area_sq_m</attrlabl>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20130916</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Environmental Science Associates - Philip Williams and Associates (ESA PWA)</cntorg>
          <cntper>Elena Vandebroek</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Hydrologist</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>550 Kearny Street, Suite 800</address>
          <city>San Francisco</city>
          <state>CA</state>
          <postal>94108</postal>
          <country>US</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(415) 262-2300</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>evandebroek@esassoc.com</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>